By clicking **“Accept All Cookies”**, you agree to the storing of cookies on your device to enhance site navigation, analyze site usage, and assist in our marketing efforts. View our [Privacy Policy](#) for more information.

Privacy Preference Center

When you visit websites, they may store or retrieve data in your browser. This storage is often necessary for the basic functionality of the website. The storage may be used for marketing, analytics, and personalization of the site, such as storing your preferences. Privacy is important to us, so you have the option of disabling certain types of storage that may not be necessary for the basic functioning of the website. Blocking categories may impact your experience on the website.

Manage Consent Preferences by Category

Essential

**Always Active**

These items are required to enable basic website functionality.

Marketing

Essential

These items are used to deliver advertising that is more relevant to you and your interests. They may also be used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement and measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. Advertising networks usually place them with the website operator’s permission.

Personalization

Essential

These items allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language, or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For example, a website may provide you with local weather reports or traffic news by storing data about your current location.

Analytics

Essential

These items help the website operator understand how its website performs, how visitors interact with the site, and whether there may be technical issues. This storage type usually doesn’t collect information that identifies a visitor.

[IT Service Desk](https://www.rezolve.ai/automated-it-helpdesk)[HR Service Desk](https://www.rezolve.ai/automated-hr-helpdesk)[

New](https://www.rezolve.ai/generative-ai)

Platform

Platform:

Where efficiency meets innovation

Industry

Industry:

Smart solutions for dynamic industries

[State & Local  
Government](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/state-and-local-government)[Education](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/education)[Retail](https://www.rezolve.ai/industry/ai-service-desk-retail)[Hospitality](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/hospitality)

[Credit Unions  
& Banks](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/credit-unions)[HealthCare](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/health-care)[MSP](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/msp)[

Construction](https://www.rezolve.ai/genai-itsm/construction)

Resources

Resources:

Discover expert insights

HIPAA
=====

Version:

Last Updated On:

#### HIPAA BUSINESS ASSOCIATE PRIVACY POLICY

We take privacy very seriously. We share a commitment with Covered Entities to protect the privacy and confidentiality of Protected Health Information (PHI) that we obtain subject to the terms of a Business Associate Agreement. This policy is provided to help you better understand how we use, disclose, and protect PHI in accordance with the terms of Business Associate Agreements.

**1\. DEFINITIONS.**In this Addendum, the following terms will have the meanings set out below:

* “Business Associate Agreement (BA Agreement)” means A formal written contract between Actionable Science and a Covered Entity that requires Actionable Science to comply with specific requirements related to PHI.
* “Covered Entity” means A health plan, healthcare provider, or healthcare clearinghouse that must comply with the HIPAA Privacy Rule.
* “Protected Health Information (PHI)” means PHI includes all “individually identifiable health information” that is transmitted or maintained in any form or medium by a Covered Entity. Individually identifiable health information is any information that can be used to identify an individual and that was created, used, or disclosed in (a) the course of providing a health care service such as diagnosis or treatment, or (b) in relation to the payment for the provision of health care services.

**2\. Use and Disclosure of PHI** We may use PHI for our management, administration, data aggregation, analytics and legal obligations to the extent such use of PHI is permitted or required by the BA Agreement and not prohibited by law. We may use or disclose PHI on behalf of, or to provide services to, Covered Entities for purposes of fulfilling our service obligations to them, if such use or disclosure of PHI is permitted or required by the BA Agreement and would not violate the HIPAA Privacy Rule.

We use third party cloud service provider. HIPAA compliant region provided by cloud service provider is used for hosting and processing PHI shared by Covered Entity. In the event that PHI must be disclosed to any other subcontractors or agents, we ensure that those subcontractors or agents agrees to abide by the same restrictions and conditions that apply to us under the BA Agreement with respect to PHI, including the implementation of reasonable and appropriate safeguards.

We may also use PHI to report violations of law to appropriate federal and state authorities.

**3\. Safeguards** We use appropriate safeguards to prevent the use or disclosure of PHI other than as provided for in the BA Agreement. We have implemented administrative, physical, and technical safeguards that reasonably and appropriately protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the electronic protected health information that we create, receive, maintain, or transmit on behalf of a Covered Entity. Such safeguards include:

* Maintaining appropriate clearance procedures and providing supervision to assure that our workforce follows appropriate security procedures;
* Providing appropriate training for our staff to assure that our staff complies with our security policies;
* Making use of appropriate encryption when transmitting PHI over the Internet;
* Utilizing appropriate storage, backup, disposal and reuse procedures to protect PHI;
* Utilizing appropriate authentication and access controls to safeguard PHI;
* Utilizing appropriate security incident procedures and providing training to our staff sufficient to detect and analyze security incidents; and
* Maintaining a current contingency plan and emergency access plan in case of an emergency to assure that the PHI we hold on behalf of a Covered Entity is available when needed.

**4\. Mitigation of Harm** In the event of a use or disclosure of PHI that is in violation of the requirements of the BA agreement, we will mitigate, to the extent practicable, any harmful effect resulting from the violation. Such mitigation will include:

* Reporting any use or disclosure of PHI not provided for by the BA Agreement and any security incident of which we become aware to the Covered Entity; and
* Documenting such disclosures of PHI and information related to such disclosures as would be required for Covered Entity to respond to a request for an accounting of disclosure of PHI in accordance with HIPAA.

**5\. Access to PHI**

As provided in the BA Agreement, we will make available to Covered Entities, information necessary for Covered Entity to give individuals their rights of access, amendment, and accounting in accordance with HIPAA regulations.

Upon request, we will make our internal practices, and records including policies and procedures, relating to the use and disclosure of PHI received from, or created or received by the BA on behalf of a Covered Entity available to the Covered Entity or the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of determining compliance with the terms of the BA Agreement and HIPAA regulations.

#### HIPAA BUSINESS ASSOCIATE PRIVACY POLICY

We take privacy very seriously. We share a commitment with Covered Entities to protect the privacy and confidentiality of Protected Health Information (PHI) that we obtain subject to the terms of a Business Associate Agreement. This policy is provided to help you better understand how we use, disclose, and protect PHI in accordance with the terms of Business Associate Agreements.

**1\. DEFINITIONS.**In this Addendum, the following terms will have the meanings set out below:

* “Business Associate Agreement (BA Agreement)” means A formal written contract between Actionable Science and a Covered Entity that requires Actionable Science to comply with specific requirements related to PHI.
* “Covered Entity” means A health plan, healthcare provider, or healthcare clearinghouse that must comply with the HIPAA Privacy Rule.
* “Protected Health Information (PHI)” means PHI includes all “individually identifiable health information” that is transmitted or maintained in any form or medium by a Covered Entity. Individually identifiable health information is any information that can be used to identify an individual and that was created, used, or disclosed in (a) the course of providing a health care service such as diagnosis or treatment, or (b) in relation to the payment for the provision of health care services.

**2\. Use and Disclosure of PHI** We may use PHI for our management, administration, data aggregation, analytics and legal obligations to the extent such use of PHI is permitted or required by the BA Agreement and not prohibited by law. We may use or disclose PHI on behalf of, or to provide services to, Covered Entities for purposes of fulfilling our service obligations to them, if such use or disclosure of PHI is permitted or required by the BA Agreement and would not violate the HIPAA Privacy Rule.

We use third party cloud service provider. HIPAA compliant region provided by cloud service provider is used for hosting and processing PHI shared by Covered Entity. In the event that PHI must be disclosed to any other subcontractors or agents, we ensure that those subcontractors or agents agrees to abide by the same restrictions and conditions that apply to us under the BA Agreement with respect to PHI, including the implementation of reasonable and appropriate safeguards.

We may also use PHI to report violations of law to appropriate federal and state authorities.

**3\. Safeguards** We use appropriate safeguards to prevent the use or disclosure of PHI other than as provided for in the BA Agreement. We have implemented administrative, physical, and technical safeguards that reasonably and appropriately protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the electronic protected health information that we create, receive, maintain, or transmit on behalf of a Covered Entity. Such safeguards include:

* Maintaining appropriate clearance procedures and providing supervision to assure that our workforce follows appropriate security procedures;
* Providing appropriate training for our staff to assure that our staff complies with our security policies;
* Making use of appropriate encryption when transmitting PHI over the Internet;
* Utilizing appropriate storage, backup, disposal and reuse procedures to protect PHI;
* Utilizing appropriate authentication and access controls to safeguard PHI;
* Utilizing appropriate security incident procedures and providing training to our staff sufficient to detect and analyze security incidents; and
* Maintaining a current contingency plan and emergency access plan in case of an emergency to assure that the PHI we hold on behalf of a Covered Entity is available when needed.

**4\. Mitigation of Harm** In the event of a use or disclosure of PHI that is in violation of the requirements of the BA agreement, we will mitigate, to the extent practicable, any harmful effect resulting from the violation. Such mitigation will include:

* Reporting any use or disclosure of PHI not provided for by the BA Agreement and any security incident of which we become aware to the Covered Entity; and
* Documenting such disclosures of PHI and information related to such disclosures as would be required for Covered Entity to respond to a request for an accounting of disclosure of PHI in accordance with HIPAA.

**5\. Access to PHI**

As provided in the BA Agreement, we will make available to Covered Entities, information necessary for Covered Entity to give individuals their rights of access, amendment, and accounting in accordance with HIPAA regulations.

Upon request, we will make our internal practices, and records including policies and procedures, relating to the use and disclosure of PHI received from, or created or received by the BA on behalf of a Covered Entity available to the Covered Entity or the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of determining compliance with the terms of the BA Agreement and HIPAA regulations.

Rezolve.ai is a Generative AI-powered modern Employee Service Desk that brings instant employee support within Microsoft Teams, reducing enterprise friction and enhancing the employee experience.

Subscribe to Newsletter

Thank you! Your submission has been received!

Oops! Something went wrong while submitting the form.

By submitting this form, you agree to receive updates and marketing material from Rezolve.ai, subject to our [Privacy Policy](https://www.rezolve.ai/legal/privacy-policy-20231017-v2-0).

Solutions

Company

Comparison

Resources

Copyright @ 2024 Rezolve.ai. All rights reserved

[ROI Calculator

New](https://www.rezolve.ai/roi-calculator)
